Mark Dean Shuler 817-243-6063

mshuler40@gmail.com GitHub / Portfolio / LinkedIn

Summary Statement

Twelve weeks in an immersive coding school retraining myself for a new career. Seven years as administrator of the knowledge management database, responsible for writing, editing, and publishing all the content for the service desk's problem management system. Personal interaction with numerous subject matter experts to manage information, contacts, and multiple deadlines simultaneously as well as being the information gathering lead on many projects.

Technical Skills

HTML	JQuery	React	Heroku	Microsoft Office
CSS	GitHub	BMC Remedy	Windows	MS Word
JavaScript	React	AWS	Mac OS	MS Excel
Software	Customer	Incident	Knowledge	MS PowerPoint
Documentation	Service	Management	Management	

Experience

7/2016 - 10/2016

The Iron Yard, Dallas, Texas

12 week immersive web development coding school

Responsibilities:

- Retraining for new career.
- 12 week curriculum that covered HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, lodash, and React.
- Teamed with two other students to redo CSS for DFW Free Code Camp.
- Final class project completed and published online.

7/2010 - 2/2016

Lockheed Martin, Fort Worth, Texas Computer Technical Support Analyst Sr / Technical Writer Responsibilities:

- Consulted with subject matter experts to develop content used by the service desk to resolve computer and software issues. Extensive use of MS Office applications to create, edit, and publish (~4000 personal; ~14000 team) Knowledge Management Repository (KMR) articles allowing the Lockheed Martin Service Desk analysts to increase their first call resolution.
- Team lead of the knowledge management database, which put me in the role of managing the information and insuring the quality of the information contained therein, and shaped the work environment for the knowledge management team.
- Lead the information gathering, writing, editing and publishing duties on over 50 projects.

Mark Dean Shuler 817-243-6063

mshuler40@gmail.com GitHub / Portfolio / LinkedIn

- Formed partnerships across business areas and organizations, allowing me to streamline the information gathering process, and give the Service Desk analysts the most current information regarding the applications they support, decreasing call times and increasing call numbers.
- Support Point of Contact for all Enterprise Operations applications creating a single point in which the service desk analysts, Tier 2 technicians, and subject matter experts could go to for assistance, or to relay changes, updates, outages, or software retirements.
- Telecommuted full-time using SharePoint, Skype for Business, instant messaging, Outlook, and phone conversations to complete group projects.
- Documented and reported software errors, and the solutions to those errors, in real time.
- Accepted a "stretch" assignment for another group assisting with the Health and Wellness centers' computers (setting them up, configuring them, and maintaining them).
- Acquired HDI certification.

3/2008 - 7/2010

Lockheed Martin, Fort Worth, Texas Remote Deskside Support Analyst

Responsibilities:

Worked incidents created by the LMSD by utilizing phone conversations and remote desktop connection software. Used advanced problem solving skills to resolve complex computer related issues. Coordinated vendor repairs on under-warranty server hardware. Wrote and edited articles for the Knowledge Management Repository.

12/2005 - 3/2008

Lockheed Martin, Denver, Colorado Defense Logistics Agency Helpdesk Analyst

Responsibilities:

Worked incidents specifically for the Defense Logistics Agency. Obtained Public Trust clearance. Performed daily remote security checks on up to 35 servers. Wrote articles for the Knowledge Management Repository.

11/1998 - 12/2005

Lockheed Martin, Denver, Colorado Helpdesk Analyst

Responsibilities:

Took computer hardware and software related calls and worked incidents specifically for the Lockheed Martin service desk. Maintained a 95% overall rating while being one of the top call takers in the call center.

Mark Dean Shuler 817-243-6063

mshuler40@gmail.com GitHub / Portfolio / LinkedIn

Education

Iron Yard

Master's Computer Information Systems, University of Phoenix - Denver, Colorado Bachelor's Business Administration, Western State - Gunnison, Colorado

Additional

Volunteer work

Joseph's Locker (Granbury, TX) – Clothing and food distribution Mission Granbury (Granbury, TX) – Food distribution

Memberships

Laguna Tres Home Owner's Association - Roads and Grounds Committee